<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no" ?>
<rfc category="exp" docName="draft-belyavskiy-fakesni-00">
<front>
<title>Fake Server Name Indication</title>
<author fullname="Dmitry Belyavskiy">
<organization abbrev="TCI">Cryptocom LTD</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>Kedrova st, 14/2</street>
<city>Moscow</city>
<code>127083</code>
<country>RU</country>
</postal>
<email>beldmit@gmail.com</email>
</address>
</author>
<date/>
<area>sec</area>
<abstract>
<t>The document provides a specification of the Fake Server Name Indication.
Being implemented, the Fake SNI specification provides a way to work around the
monitoring solutions without providing any additional information to external
observers.</t>
</abstract>
</front>
<middle>
<section title="Introduction">
<t>Many DPI solutions use SNI information as a criteria to filter connection to
various sites.  Though Encrypted SNI makes impossible to read the SNI value,
there is <eref
target="https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/msg/tls/WiT3oEh6PO96mm0z28BNMp0YgGs">information</eref>
that absense of SNI looks suspicious itself and all communication is blocked.
</t> 
<t>This specification introduces a way to provide a value of SNI treated
by TLS server as an alias to one of the names known by server but not matching
the possibly suspicious host name.</t>
</section>
<section title="Fake SNI design goals">

<t> The solution specified in this document is inspired by the design of Encrypted SNI</t>

<t>The provider publishes a name matching the target name to be provided in
clear text.  This document defines a publication mechanism using DNS, but other
mechanisms are also possible.</t> 
<t> When a client wants to establish a TLS connection to a domain served by an
Fake SNI-supporting provider, it replaces the value in "server_name" extension
in the ClientHello with the value obtained by transport.  The provider can then
find out the desired name from its configuration and either establish the
connection with the desired host or reject it.</t>
</section>

<section title="Fake SNI indication"></section>
<section title="Client behaviour"></section>
<section title="Server behaviour"></section>
<section title="Security considerations"></section>
</middle>
</rfc>
