<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no" ?>
<rfc category="exp" docName="draft-belyavskiy-fakesni-01">
<front>
<title>Fake Server Name Indication</title>
<author fullname="Dmitry Belyavskiy">
<organization abbrev="TCI">Cryptocom LTD</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>Kedrova st, 14/2</street>
<city>Moscow</city>
<code>127083</code>
<country>RU</country>
</postal>
<email>beldmit@gmail.com</email>
</address>
</author>
<date/>
<area>sec</area>
<abstract>
<t>The document provides a specification of the Fake Server Name Indication.
Being implemented, the Fake SNI specification provides a way to work around the
monitoring solutions without providing any additional information to external
observers.</t>
</abstract>
</front>
<middle>

<section title="Introduction">
<t>Many DPI solutions use SNI information as a criterion to filter connection to
various sites.  Though Encrypted SNI makes impossible to read the SNI value,
there is <eref
target="https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/msg/tls/WiT3oEh6PO96mm0z28BNMp0YgGs">information</eref>
that absence of SNI looks suspicious itself and all communications are blocked.
</t> 

<t>This specification introduces a way to provide a value of SNI treated
by TLS server as an alias to one of the names known by server but not matching
the possibly suspicious hostname.</t>

<t>This specification does not save from DPI solutions but it provides one more
loophole to cheat them.</t>
</section>

<section title="Fake SNI design goals">
<t>The solution specified in this document is inspired by the design of Encrypted SNI.</t>

<t>The provider publishes a name matching the target name to be provided in the
clear text. This document defines a publication mechanism using DNS, but other
mechanisms are also possible.</t>

<t> When a client wants to establish a TLS connection to a domain served by a
Fake SNI-supporting provider, it replaces the value in "server_name" extension
in the ClientHello with the value obtained by transport.  The provider can then
find out the desired name from its configuration and either establish the
connection with the desired host or reject it.</t>
</section>

<section title="Definitions">
<t>
<list>
<t>Original name - the hostname of service that is subject to hide.</t>
<t>Fake name - the hostname specified by server and sent by client to indicate
intention to connect to host with original name.</t>
</list>
</t>
</section>

<section title="Fake SNI indication">
<t> Fake SNI information is published in DNS via TXT RR. For example, the Fake
SNI record for domain example.com may look like</t>

<t>
_fakesni.example.com. 60S IN TXT "myfakerecord.com IP"
</t>

<t>
where IP address may be omitted. If present, it MUST match an IP address
specified in A/AAAA record for the domain.
</t>

<t>Value specified in the Fake SNI RR MUST NOT match any hostname available for
the IP address it is valid for.  Fake names for different hosts MUST be
different.</t>

</section>

<section title="Server behaviour">
<t>On receiveing the value of known Fake SNI in the TLS ClientHello server
MUST return the certificate matching the original hostname. Otherwise server
SHOULD abort the connection.
</t>
</section>

<section title="Client behaviour">
<t>
Client MAY use the Fake SNI record as fallback if connecting using ESNI is
blocked. In this case client initiates normal TLS connection specifying the
value from Fake SNI record in the server_name extension. If the certificate
received from server does not match the original hostname, the client
MUST abort the connection. Otherwise the client MUST follow the normal process
of TLS handshake.
</t>
</section>

<section title="Security considerations">
<t>As Fake SNI can be used in TLS 1.2, it does not provide any problems to DPI
because in this case the original hostname is available in clear text in server
certificate.  TLS 1.3 encrypts the Certificate message, so it is RECOMMENDED to
use Fake SNI together with TLS 1.3.  To strengthen the protection, it's
recommended to obtain _fakesni RR via DoT or DoH.</t>

<t>As DPI solutions are able to obtain the DNS _fakesni records as legitimate
clients do, it is RECOMMENDED to set reasonable TTL values for the _fakesni
records. Also it is RECOMMENDED to use such values of fake names that are
syntactically correct domain names. Otherwise DPI can recognise the fake names
as fake ones.</t>
</section>
</middle>
</rfc>
